<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ming Su on Ming Su | 苏命</title>
    <link>/authors/ming-su/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ming Su on Ming Su | 苏命</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; [Ming Su](/) 2014 -2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 22:08:42 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/ming-su/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Final report of project &#39;su2018jinze&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/su2018jinze_progress2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 22:08:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/su2018jinze_progress2018/</guid>
      <description>Final report of project &amp;lsquo;su2018jinze&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown snippet for Hugo post</title>
      <link>/post/20190129_markdownexample/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 15:30:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190129_markdownexample/</guid>
      <description>The solutions are mainly derived from Yihui&amp;rsquo;s JS library. Code By using: ` ` `r a &amp;lt;- 1 + 1 ... ` ` ` produces: a = 1 + 1 ... MathJax Solution: Add math-code.js. to static/js/. Add the following lines to layouts/partials/footer_section.html. &amp;lt;!-- 加入MathJax, 用于Markdown中输入数学公</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A book for phytoplankton identification</title>
      <link>/post/20190128_phytoplanktonidentification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 12:30:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190128_phytoplanktonidentification/</guid>
      <description>A book for phytoplankton Identification.
Fulltext link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Report for Project &#39;su2015miyunnsf&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/20190125_su2015miyunnsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 12:30:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20190125_su2015miyunnsf/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Miyun Reservoir, the most important surface source water for Beijing, has been suffered water crisis due to continuous drought and over-extraction during recent years; the Central Route of South-to-North Water Diversion Project (SNWDP) is expect to transfer water from Danjiangkou Reservoir to Miyun Reservoir in order to resolve the water shortage. The SNWDP will be bound to solve release the water crisis in the respect of “wa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humic acid removal by gas–liquid interface discharge plasma: performance, mechanism and comparison to ozonation</title>
      <link>/publication/cui-2019-humic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cui-2019-humic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of musty odorants on septic odor: Verification in Huangpu River source water</title>
      <link>/publication/guo-2019-synergistic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/guo-2019-synergistic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>西安建筑科技大学水库研究交流</title>
      <link>/talk/20181121_%E8%A5%BF%E5%AE%89%E5%BB%BA%E7%AD%91%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A4%A7%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%A4%E6%B5%81/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/20181121_%E8%A5%BF%E5%AE%89%E5%BB%BA%E7%AD%91%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A4%A7%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%A4%E6%B5%81/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>水源研究梳理</title>
      <link>/talk/20180831_%E6%B0%B4%E5%BA%93%E7%A0%94%E7%A9%B6%E8%AE%A8%E8%AE%BA/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/20180831_%E6%B0%B4%E5%BA%93%E7%A0%94%E7%A9%B6%E8%AE%A8%E8%AE%BA/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Succession and interaction of surface and subsurface cyanobacterial blooms in oligotrophic/mesotrophic reservoirs: a case study in Miyun Reservoir</title>
      <link>/publication/su-2019-succession/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su-2019-succession/</guid>
      <description> Highlights  High light and nutrient at pre-bloom stage are essential for surface cyanobacteria. Surface cell decline enhanced underwater light thus promoted subsurface cyanobacteria. Subsurface cyanobacteria prefer to grow in shallow oligotrophic/deep eutrophic water.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster@ISME17</title>
      <link>/talk/20180813_isme17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 15:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/20180813_isme17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart monitoring and management system of source water</title>
      <link>/publication/smartsourcewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/smartsourcewater/</guid>
      <description>Software Information Version: v1.0 No.: 2018SR539952 主要功能 在云平台中整合水源地在线和实验室监测分析数据，通过实时获取监测数据、在线展示数据图表、时空趋势分析以及水质模型预警等功能</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odor problem of Qingcaosha Reservoir</title>
      <link>/post/qcsodor2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/qcsodor2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report of Qingcaosha Reservoir regarding the investigation on May 23, 2018</title>
      <link>/post/qcs180523/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/qcs180523/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report of odor problem of source water reservoir in East Tai Lake in June of 2018</title>
      <link>/post/wujiang180607/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/wujiang180607/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud analysis system of phytoplankton data in source water</title>
      <link>/publication/algaemanagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/algaemanagement/</guid>
      <description>Software information Version: v1.0 No.: 2018SR539959 Functions 在云平台中基于用户需求定制藻类分析，获取实时藻类数据，优势藻种类、有害藻 种类、不同藻种的时空分布及趋势分析;定制报告。 Features 基于L</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell Counting Tool v1.4</title>
      <link>/publication/cctv1.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cctv1.4/</guid>
      <description>Software Information Version: v1.4 No.: 2018SR525480 Introduction 辅助显微镜下细胞计数，藻类数据库查询，计数数据、镜检图片自动归档，数据分析，可视化。 技术特点 结合显微镜计数原理，将传统机械式计</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/20190126_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/20190126_test/</guid>
      <description>Slides can be added in a few ways:
 Create slides using Academic’s Slides feature and link using url_slides parameter in the front matter of the talk file Upload an existing slide deck to static/ and link using url_slides parameter in the front matter of the talk file Embed your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using shortcodes.  Further talk details can easily be added to this page using RMarkdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing production of taste and odor by deep-living cyanobacteria in drinking water reservoirs by regulation of water level</title>
      <link>/publication/su-2017-reducing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su-2017-reducing/</guid>
      <description> Highlights  Water level lowering triggered the deep living cyanobacteria bloom in Miyun Reservoir. The shallow areas in Miyun Reservoir are the major habitats for Planktothrix sp. The Planktothrix could bloom in mesotrophic water due to its low light requirement.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source-water odor during winter in the Yellow River area of China: Occurrence and diagnosis</title>
      <link>/publication/li-2016-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/li-2016-source/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of odor-producing Planktothrix sp. in Miyun Reservoir, regarding the ecological niche identification, regulation and control strategy</title>
      <link>/publication/su2015study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su2015study/</guid>
      <description>MIB producing potential of Planktothrix sp. The production of odorant methylisoborneol (MIB) in water bodies by Planktothrix sp. have not been understood very well. Through a four-year investigation in Miyun Reservoir, a huge mesotrophic drinking water reservoir known to have the MIB episodes, we found that the Planktothrix sp. bloomed during September and October causing the high levels of MIB in the reservoir. The concentration of MIB and the biomass of MIB-producing cyanobacteria Planktothrix sp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorate tools list</title>
      <link>/post/20150216_favoratetools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 12:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20150216_favoratetools/</guid>
      <description>I prefer to use command line tools (CLI). Here is a list that I am using and enjoying.
 OS: debian/ubuntu (95%) + windows(5%) windows manager: FVWM reminder: conky+remind+wyrd calendar: conky+remind+web shell: zsh+tmux mail: mutt/getmail/msmtp contactor: abook document (doc): markdown (60%) + MS word (30%, under windows) + wps (10%) presentation: MS powerpoint (70%, under windows) + html5 slides (30%) scientific publish/thesis: latex (texlive) pdf reader: okular note: note editor: vim remote operating: ssh remote desktop: remmina virtual OS: virtualbox database: mysql file manager: ranger internet expolor: firefox + uzbl ftp: lftpd image editor: gimp music player: mocp video player: vlc data analysis: R/matlab/python dictionary: iciba.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIB-producing cyanobacteria (Planktothrix sp.) in a drinking water reservoir: Distribution and odor producing potential</title>
      <link>/publication/su-2015-mib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su-2015-mib/</guid>
      <description> Highlights  Water level lowering triggered the deep living cyanobacteria bloom in Miyun Reservoir. The shallow areas in Miyun Reservoir are the major habitats for Planktothrix sp. The Planktothrix could bloom in mesotrophic water due to its low light requirement.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple linear regression model for bromate formation based on the survey data of source waters from geographically different regions across China</title>
      <link>/publication/yu-2015-multiple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/yu-2015-multiple/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup MySQL connection using R in GNU linux</title>
      <link>/post/20141221_mysql_skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 19:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20141221_mysql_skill/</guid>
      <description> Aim To connect mysql database using R is very important if you want to do some data analysis, I have extreamly bad experience on setting up it in GNU/linux, as I know, it is not easy to setup in windows as well.
 Install Install libmysqlclient-dev sudo apt-get install libmysqlclient-dev  download and install RMySQL wget http://cran.r-project.org/src/contrib/RMySQL_0.9-3.tar.gz R CMD INSTALL --configure-args=&amp;#39;--with-mysql-dir=/usr/lib&amp;#39; RMySQL_0.9-3.tar.gz    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using kermit for downloading data from YSI-terminal 650MDS under linux</title>
      <link>/post/20141209_ysi_skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 18:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20141209_ysi_skill/</guid>
      <description>Aim The offical ECO-Watch software only support on Windows systems.
By using kermit, we can simply download data in YSI-terminal 650DMS through serial port connection.
 Installation  apt-get install ckermit or
yum install ckermit or
pacman -S ckermit  configuration cat ~/.kermrc set line /dev/ttyUSB0 set speed 9600 set carrier-watch off set handshake none set flow-control none robust set parity none set stop-bits 1 set file type bin set file name lit set rec pack 1000 set send pack 1000 set window 5  usage On linux terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download or upload waypoints or tracks from gps under GNU linux by gpsbabel</title>
      <link>/post/20141209_gps_skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 17:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20141209_gps_skill/</guid>
      <description>Aim I have got a garmin etrex gps which is very old but working pretty well; its major work is for sampling sites navigation in lakes/reservoirs.
By using GPSbabel, I can easily download/upload waypoints/tracks from gps devices under GNU linux.
 communication through rs232 protocal My workstation doesn’t have a serial port, so I use a usb2serial cable for doing this. In my case, I could find my serial device here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The solution for Google searching in mainland China</title>
      <link>/post/20141206_google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20141206_google/</guid>
      <description>I have recently found a good solution for searching with google.
It is not based on vpn nor host file.
Just simply use
http://www.gfsoso.com
for google main sites
and use
http://www.gfsoso.com/scholar
for google scholar,
and so on.
Good luck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t let your tear be the last drop of water in the world- my peasonal logo</title>
      <link>/post/20141123_tear_tobe_last_water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 21:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20141123_tear_tobe_last_water/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by
 Don’t let your tear be the last drop of water in the world
 I designed my peasonal logo.
My peasonal logo
This logo is basically composed of two drop tears and one drop water. The water-drop in the left side means the last drop water in the world, but also it means all bios in the planet share the same drop of water.
Water give the planet life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule your time by using remind, wyrd, conky as well as rem2html</title>
      <link>/post/201411121_schedule_by_remind_wyrd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 21:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/201411121_schedule_by_remind_wyrd/</guid>
      <description>How do you schedule your time? I was using gcalcli for couple years, however, it is become very difficult to use in mainland China, due to the GFW policy; on the other hand, I prefer to using my own server other than using the server from others, in this case google calendar.
So I start to find a better solution. Fortunately, I managed it by using remind, wyrd, conky and rem2html.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>土豪与屌丝</title>
      <link>/post/20141209_tuhao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 13:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20141209_tuhao/</guid>
      <description>正常人： 屌丝: 土豪：</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a bash command to post on jekyll based blog</title>
      <link>/post/20141102_jekyll_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20141102_jekyll_blog/</guid>
      <description>It is very time-consuming to write up the HEADLINE of your each post. This article is aiming to show you a bash command based way to set up the HEADLINE in the post.
#!/bin/bash ## ~/bin/wa hppath=&amp;quot;~/u2/www/homepage&amp;quot; d=`date &amp;#39;+%Y-%m-%d&amp;#39;` t=`date &amp;#39;+%b %d, %Y %H:%M:%S&amp;#39;` filename=${1// /_} head=&amp;quot;---\n&amp;quot; cd ~/u2/www/homepage/_posts/ postpath=&amp;quot;~/u2/www/homepage/_posts&amp;quot; # touch $d&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;$filename&amp;quot;.md&amp;quot;` echo -e &amp;quot;$head&amp;quot; &amp;gt; &amp;quot;$d&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;$filename&amp;quot;.md vim &amp;quot;$d&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;$filename&amp;quot;.md Add execute permission on this file:
chmod +x ~/bin/wa Usage:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer risk assessment on trihalomethanes and haloacetic acids in drinking water of China using disability-adjusted life years</title>
      <link>/publication/pan-2014-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pan-2014-cancer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of underwater light field in selecting phytoplankton morphology in a eutrophic reservoir</title>
      <link>/publication/su-2014-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su-2014-important/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishment of quantitative PCR methods for the quantification of geosmin-producing potential and Anabaena sp. in freshwater systems</title>
      <link>/publication/su-2013-establishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su-2013-establishment/</guid>
      <description> Highlights  We designed primers targeting for Anabaena rpoC₁ gene and geosmin synthase gene. We constructed two qPCR assays aim for quantifying general Anabaena population and geosmin-produce potential. Both qPCR were verified by simulated culture bloom and field samples, hence are applicable. Compared to traditional methods, the two qPCR assays provide fast, simple and on-site approach.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algal growth dynamics in drinking water reservoir and the driving force</title>
      <link>/publication/su2013algal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su2013algal/</guid>
      <description>Rapid detection method of Anabaena associated with odorous compound based on qPCR in freshwater system: Geosmin has often been associated with off-flavor problems in drinking water with Anabaena sp. as the major producer. Rapid on-site detection of geosmin-producers as well as geosmin is important for a timely management response to potential off-flavor events. In this study, quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qPCR) methods were developed to detect the levels of Anabaena sp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial and temporal variations of two cyanobacteria in the mesotrophic Miyun reservoir, China</title>
      <link>/publication/su-2014-spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/su-2014-spatial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fishy odor episode in a north China reservoir: Occurrence, origin, and possible odor causing compounds</title>
      <link>/publication/zhao-2013-fishy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/zhao-2013-fishy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>