<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planktothrix on Ming Su | 苏命</title>
    <link>http://suming.me/tags/planktothrix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planktothrix on Ming Su | 苏命</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; [Ming Su](/) 2014 -2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 12:30:55 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://suming.me/tags/planktothrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A book for phytoplankton identification</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/post/20190128_phytoplanktonidentification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 12:30:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/post/20190128_phytoplanktonidentification/</guid>
      <description>A book for phytoplankton Identification.
link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Report for Project &#39;su2015miyunnsf&#39;</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/post/20190125_su2015miyunnsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 12:30:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/post/20190125_su2015miyunnsf/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Miyun Reservoir, the most important surface source water for Beijing, has been suffered water crisis due to continuous drought and over-extraction during recent years; the Central Route of South-to-North Water Diversion Project (SNWDP) is expect to transfer water from Danjiangkou Reservoir to Miyun Reservoir in order to resolve the water shortage. The SNWDP will be bound to solve release the water crisis in the respect of “wa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of central route of South-to- North Water Diversion Project to the growth of odor-producing cyanobacteria in Miyun Reservoir</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/project/su2015miyunnsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/project/su2015miyunnsf/</guid>
      <description>Project Information  From: the National Science Foundation of China Founding: ￥0.24 M Host: Ming Su Period: 2015&amp;frasl;01 - 2018&amp;frasl;12 Grant No.: 5150081984  Abstract Miyun Reservoir, the most important surface source water for Beijing, has been suffered water crisis due to continuous drought and over-extraction during recent years; the Central Route of South-to-North Water Diversion Project (SNWDP) is expect to transfer water from Danjiangkou Reservoir to Miyun Reservoir in order to resolve the water shortage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing production of taste and odor by deep-living cyanobacteria in drinking water reservoirs by regulation of water level</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/publication/su-2017-reducing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/publication/su-2017-reducing/</guid>
      <description> Highlights  Water level lowering triggered the deep living cyanobacteria bloom in Miyun Reservoir. The shallow areas in Miyun Reservoir are the major habitats for Planktothrix sp. The Planktothrix could bloom in mesotrophic water due to its low light requirement.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of odor-producing Planktothrix sp. in Miyun Reservoir, regarding the ecological niche identification, regulation and control strategy</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/publication/su2015study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/publication/su2015study/</guid>
      <description>MIB producing potential of Planktothrix sp. The production of odorant methylisoborneol (MIB) in water bodies by Planktothrix sp. have not been understood very well. Through a four-year investigation in Miyun Reservoir, a huge mesotrophic drinking water reservoir known to have the MIB episodes, we found that the Planktothrix sp. bloomed during September and October causing the high levels of MIB in the reservoir. The concentration of MIB and the biomass of MIB-producing cyanobacteria Planktothrix sp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIB-producing cyanobacteria (Planktothrix sp.) in a drinking water reservoir: Distribution and odor producing potential</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/publication/su-2015-mib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/publication/su-2015-mib/</guid>
      <description> Highlights  Water level lowering triggered the deep living cyanobacteria bloom in Miyun Reservoir. The shallow areas in Miyun Reservoir are the major habitats for Planktothrix sp. The Planktothrix could bloom in mesotrophic water due to its low light requirement.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>