<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>State Founded on Ming Su | 苏命</title>
    <link>http://suming.me/tags/state-founded/</link>
    <description>Recent content in State Founded on Ming Su | 苏命</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; [Ming Su](/) 2014 -2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 22:28:44 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://suming.me/tags/state-founded/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of water quality of source water reservoirs in typical cities</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/project/su2019casreservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 22:28:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/project/su2019casreservoir/</guid>
      <description> Project Information  From: Chinese Academy of Science Founding: ￥0.20 M Host: Ming Su Period: Jan, 2019 - Dec, 2021 Grant No.: KFJ-SW-YW036  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-situ control of filamentous odor-producing cyanobacteria based on underwater light lowering technology in source water reservoirs: mechanism and strategy development</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/project/su2018miyunnsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/project/su2018miyunnsf/</guid>
      <description>Project Information  From: the National Science Foundation of China Founding: ￥0.60 M Host: Ming Su Period: Jan, 2019 - Dec, 2022 Grant No.: 51878649  Abstract The off-flavour problems caused by filamentous cyanobacteria in source water reservoirs have been frequently recorded in China, some of these cyanobacterial strains are able to produce 2-Methylisoborneol (2-MIB), an earthy/musty odorant. 2-MIB, with an extremely low odor threshold can not be effectively removed by conventional water treatment process, and thus threatens water supply safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control strategies of odor problem in source water, water quality problem in drinking water treatment plant and leakage problem in pipe netwaork</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/project/su2017135/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/project/su2017135/</guid>
      <description>Project Information From: The National Water Pollution Control and Treatment Science and Technology Major Project Founding: ￥1.20 M Host: Ming Su Period: Jan, 2017 - Jun, 2020 Grant No.: 2017ZX07108-002 Project Tasks 密云水库水源地嗅味问题控制策略研究 密云水库近年来由于局部区域丝状蓝藻</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification, control technology and demostration of typical odorants in drinking water</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/project/yu2015odorwp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/project/yu2015odorwp/</guid>
      <description>Project Information From: The National Water Pollution Control and Treatment Science and Technology Major Project Founding: ￥29.60 M Host: Jianwei Yu Period: Jan, 2015 - Dec, 2017 Grant No.: 2015ZX07406001 Project Tasks 任务1 饮用水嗅味感官评价方法研究以重点流域为主要对象开展饮用水嗅味</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechansim of cyanobacterial bloom and harmful by-product in source water reservoirs and lakes</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/project/yang2010miyunnsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/project/yang2010miyunnsf/</guid>
      <description>Project Information  From: State Key Program of National Natural Science of China Founding: ￥2 M Host: Min Yang Period: Jan, 2010 - Dec, 2013 Grant No.: 50938007  Abstract In recent years, cyanobacterial blooming in lakes and reservoirs is becoming more and more frequent, which has caused serious concerns regarding the drinking water safety posed by harmful algal metabolites such as odor and toxin substances. In this project, two source water reservoirs in north China (Miyun Reservoir and Yanghe Reservoir), which are in different nutrition states, were selected as the research targets, and the responding mechanisms of algae to nutrition and hydraulic conditions, as well as the physical, chemical and biological mechanisms for the production of odor-causing compounds and algal toxins were systematically studied by combining the on-site observation approaches with microcosm simulation methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response solution and treatment research for high algal cell density loding of canal water from South-to-North Water Diversion Project</title>
      <link>http://suming.me/project/yu2016snwpbwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suming.me/project/yu2016snwpbwa/</guid>
      <description>Project Information From: Beijing Water Authority&amp;rdquo; Founding: ￥0.50 M Host: Jianwei Yu Period: Jan, 2016 - Dec, 2016 Introduction 南水北调水源进京后，极大的缓解了北京市用水紧张的局面。然而由于南 北水源水质的差异，一定程度上又</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>